<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>de.kiefer_networks.sshvault</id>
  <name>SSHVault</name>
  <summary>Zero-knowledge encrypted SSH and terminal client</summary>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>LicenseRef-proprietary</project_license>

  <description>
    <p>
      SSHVault is a secure SSH client with zero-knowledge encrypted
      sync across devices. Manage SSH connections, keys, and snippets
      with end-to-end encryption — the server never sees your data.
    </p>
    <p>Features:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>SSH terminal with full xterm emulation</li>
      <li>SFTP file browser</li>
      <li>SSH key management (Ed25519, RSA, ECDSA)</li>
      <li>Encrypted snippet library</li>
      <li>Zero-knowledge sync with AES-256-GCM and Argon2id</li>
      <li>Connection grouping and tagging</li>
      <li>Encrypted export/import</li>
    </ul>
  </description>

  <url type="homepage">https://sshvault.app</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/Kiefer-Networks/sshvault/issues</url>

  <developer id="de.kiefer_networks">
    <name>Kiefer Networks</name>
  </developer>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">de.kiefer_networks.sshvault.desktop</launchable>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

  <releases>
    <release version="1.11.0" date="2026-04-26">
      <description>
        <p>Linux desktop integration pass: ssh:// + sftp:// URL handlers, system tray (AppIndicator/SNI) with favorites and active sessions, DBus service de.kiefer_networks.SSHVault for single-instance + external triggers from rofi/polybar/KRunner, KRunner plugin, libsecret-backed master-key storage in GNOME Keyring / KWallet, ssh-agent integration so git/scp/ansible/vscode-remote-ssh can use SSHVault keys, follow GNOME / KDE preferred color scheme via xdg-desktop-portal, and drag-and-drop SSH keys onto the window to auto-import.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.10.6" date="2026-04-26">
      <description>
        <p>Android: liboqs.so is now built with 16 KB ELF page alignment so Google Play accepts the upload on Android 15+ devices. Other native libs (libflutter, libapp, libsqlite3) were already aligned.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.10.5" date="2026-04-26">
      <description>
        <p>Drops READ_MEDIA_IMAGES / READ_MEDIA_VIDEO permission inherited from image_picker so Google Play accepts the upload (the app uses the Photo Picker, which needs no permission). Android disconnects now appear as a system-shade notification with an inline Reconnect action button; the prior in-app slide-up dialog is gone.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.10.4" date="2026-04-26">
      <description>
        <p>Android now uses the OS notification shade instead of in-app SnackBar overlays so messages no longer cover the UI. List padding above the FAB cluster bumped to 144 dp so the floating add/search buttons no longer sit on top of the last server tile's edit / info actions.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.10.3" date="2026-04-26">
      <description>
        <p>Fixes hybrid post-quantum SSH KEX wire format and shared-secret derivation against OpenSSH 9.9+ servers — mlkem768x25519 client public-key blob now sends the KEM half before the X25519 half, server reply parsing matches, and the resulting shared secret is HASH(kem_ss || x25519_ss) (SHA-256 for ML-KEM, SHA-512 for sntrup761) before being string-encoded into the exchange hash. 1.10.2 negotiated the algorithm but failed at the first encrypted packet.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.10.2" date="2026-04-26">
      <description>
        <p>CI fix: Flatpak liboqs module now uses CMAKE_INSTALL_LIBDIR instead of the meson-style --libdir flag (cmake-ninja rejected the latter).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.10.1" date="2026-04-26">
      <description>
        <p>Fixes liboqs Flatpak SHA256 mismatch and reduces the per-platform liboqs build to just ML-KEM-768 and sntrup761 so the macOS, Windows, Android and Flatpak release jobs finish without exhausting the runner's process table.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.10.0" date="2026-04-26">
      <description>
        <p>Adds hybrid post-quantum SSH key exchange (mlkem768x25519-sha256, sntrup761x25519-sha512@openssh.com) via the Open Quantum Safe liboqs library. Connects to OpenSSH 9.9+ servers configured for PQ-only KEX without breaking classical fallback.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.9.3" date="2026-04-26">
      <description>
        <p>Format pass fixes CI; no behavior changes from 1.9.2.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.9.2" date="2026-04-26">
      <description>
        <p>Connect dialog now explains which SSH algorithm class (KEX, cipher, MAC, host key) the server requires when none overlap with the client. README documents supported algorithms.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.9.1" date="2026-04-26">
      <description>
        <p>Fixes a widget test regression by routing native desktop notifications through defaultTargetPlatform; ships regenerated localization bindings.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.9.0" date="2026-04-26">
      <description>
        <p>Sync now propagates deletes via tombstones and uses per-entity last-write-wins for renames and reorders, fixing data resurrecting between devices.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.8.0" date="2026-04-26">
      <description>
        <p>System notifications on Linux and Windows; redesigned folder section headers; grid view honors mode toggle; search moved to FAB; expanded icon library; min/max/close window controls on Linux.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.0" date="2026-03-03">
      <description>
        <p>Initial release.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>

  <requires>
    <display_length compare="ge">768</display_length>
  </requires>

  <supports>
    <control>pointing</control>
    <control>keyboard</control>
  </supports>

  <provides>
    <mediatype>x-scheme-handler/ssh</mediatype>
    <mediatype>x-scheme-handler/sftp</mediatype>
    <mediatype>application/x-sshvault-export</mediatype>
  </provides>
</component>
